# 倍儿挺看着 饱满
Looks very firm and full
# 这老两位 大爷和二伯 配合默契
These two, Da Ye and Er Bai cooperate tacitly
# 也是会享受生活的好男人
They are good men who know how to enjoy life
# 炸个小黄鱼
Fried small yellow croaker
# 这是最家常的
This is a homestyle dish
# 咱们今天买这个是没去头没去肠
What we bought today is whole, with head and intestine
# 留了几条给大家演示一下
I left a few to demonstrate (on how to clean it)
# 这里边有个小肠子给它清理干净
Here is the small intestine, clean it up
# 这就干净了
This is clean now
# 干炸好吃
Deep fried (yellow croaker) is delicious
# 腌这个特别简单
Marinade this is very easy
# 花椒
Sichuan Pepper
# 腌这个就是现在马上就炸
Marinade this, if you are going to fry it right now
# 盐稍微重一点
Use a bit more salt
# 说腌 一会儿两小时以后才吃呢
If you marinade and plan to eat after two hours
# 那就稍微薄一点
Use less salt
# 少来一点点味精
A little bit of MSG
# 这个味精是提味
Use MSG to enhance the flavor
# 有些原料它没什么特殊的味道
Some ingredients have no special taste
# 我们还要补充一点味道
We have to add a bit of flavor
# 黄酒
Huangjiu Rice wine
# 我们还得搁点葱姜
We need to add some green onion and ginger
# 腌这鱼就用点葱尾巴
Marinating this fish only requires small amount of the end part of green onion
# 而且它腌的也容易出味
And it's easy to release its tastes
# 大约腌十五分钟
Marinate for about 15 minutes
# 下面咱就焙点椒盐 完了再调糊
Let's toast some Sichuan pepper salt and make the batter afterwards
# 这花椒盐就是现焙现用 别太多
This pepper salt should be freshly toasted, so don’t make too much
# 吃不了过两天味没了
If you can't finish it, the aroma will be gone after a few days
# 大爷为什么加点味精
Da Ye, why do you add some MSG?
# 不加味精还真不鲜 就这鱼挺怪
It's not umami without MSG, this fish is pretty weird
# 有些东西必须得加点
Some things must be added
# 因为它本身没有什么
Because it has nothing,
# 其它的味道 除了腥
Other smells except fishy
# 花椒焙好了 晾一晾
The peppercorns are toasted. Let it dry and cool down
# 大爷 焙花椒的火候
Da Ye, the temperature to toast pepper
# 是不是有一个讲究
Is there a particular (temperature)?
# 基本上是以小火
Basically with low heat
# 焙的稍微焦糊一点 出香味为准
Toast till slightly burnt. When the aroma release, it is done
# 这花椒不能焙的太嫩是吧 对
Sichuan pepper cannot be under-toasted, right?
# 稍微过一点 因为它里边你焙不透
Over-toast it a little bit, because (otherwise) the inside might not have been toasted thoroughly
# 擀一下你看
Crush it with rolling pin, see
# 它火候到了自然一擀就碎
If it is well cooked, it break easily when you crush it
# 待会凉了之后更好擀了
It will be easier after it gets cold
# 家里边炸小黄鱼 不加鸡蛋
Fried small yellow croaker at home without eggs,
# 完全是面糊 不太香
but only flour batter, is not very fragrant
# 搁点鸡蛋 是起一个增香的作用
Add some egg and it will enhance the fragrance
# 另外挂糊比较饱满
In addition, the batter will be fuller
# 所以这鸡蛋不宜太多
No need for too many eggs
# 有一个就足矣了
Just one is enough
# 全蛋是吧 全蛋
Whole egg, right? Whole egg
# 面粉  我这不是软炸糊
Flour, this is not soft fried batter
# 在软炸糊的基础上 给做了一些调整
I made some adjustments on the basis of soft fried batter
# 软炸糊就是鸡蛋面粉
Soft fried batter is (using) egg and flour
# 有些网友可能在纠结说
Some netizens may think
# 软炸糊不搁淀粉
Soft fried batter does not include starch
# 不是 根据原材料的水分和它的质地
No necessarily. Based on the moisture and texture of the raw material
# 你要适当的加点淀粉
You need to add some starch
# 为什么 增加它的脆感
Why? To increase its crispness
# 水分别流失的太多
Avoid losing too much water
# 这鱼炸得又要焦脆 但是还要鲜嫩
This fish need to fry till crispy but still need to be tender
# 你不能炸那鱼跟干炸鱼似的
You can't fry the fish like dry fried fish
# 那叫干炸小黄鱼 这个是带点糊的
It's called dry fried yellow croaker. This one is with batter.
# 三分之一的淀粉 还得给点水
One-third of starch, and add some water
# 面粉和淀粉的比例是二比一
The ratio of flour to starch is two to one
# 二的面粉 一的淀粉
2 portions of flour, 1 portion starch
# 这个糊因为咱们鱼刚才腌了 也看了
This batter, because our fish was marinated just now
# 比较干 控水控的比较干
And relatively dry, no extra water
# 所以这个糊稍微让它稀一点
So let this batter be a little thinner
# 最关键最关键就是这糊 这就好啦
The most important thing is this batter. That's it
# 亮子 有时候咱们做饭
Liangzi, sometimes when we cook
# 还得掌握一个时间差
We need to master a time difference
# 油烧上 花椒刚才二伯给擀了擀
Preheat the oil. Er Bai crushed the pepper just now
# 你看这个程序
Look at this procedure
# 择完鱼腌鱼 腌完鱼擀花椒
Clean fish, marinate fish, and then crush Sichuan pepper
# 我们还要过滤一下
We have to filter it
# 这个细的花椒面是蘸椒盐用的
This fine pepper powder is for Sichuan pepper salt
# 粗的干嘛的呢 别扔
What do you do with the coarse pepper powder? Don't throw it away
# 那个是炒菜的时候
That is for cooking
# 比如做麻婆豆腐 给炒到里头
Like making Mapo Tofu, use that.
# 不能浪费
Shouldn’t waste ingredients
# 齐活 齐了
All done
# 这椒盐真香
This Sichuan pepper salt is really fragrant
# 椒盐怎么兑呢 一比一两勺盐
How to make Sichuan pepper salt? One to one, two tablespoons of salt
# 然后这个味精是一定要加的
Then this MSG must be added
# 椒盐里边也得加味精
MSG must be added to the Sichuan pepper salt
# 必须加 必须得加味精
Must add MSG
# 它就吃出来鲜了
It's umami
# 为什么说他的黄鱼好吃呢
Why is his yellow croaker delicious?
# 捏这椒盐到什么颜色
Mix the Sichuan pepper salt to what extent?
# 一定要看点白的 沙沙的盐
Must see some white, sandy-like salt
# 特别好看 这个椒盐就算齐了
It's so pretty. This Sichuan pepper salt is ready
# 这油锅也差不多了 油锅也热了
This oil is almost heated
# 然后您的鱼 我给您放过来 得
Then your fish. Let me put it here for you. Good.
# 谢谢二伯 我就是老饭骨小助手
Thank you, Er Bai. I'm your assistant
# 这花椒不用择出来
No need to pick this Sichuan pepper out
# 花椒一会搁里都不要紧
It doesn't matter if you leave the peppercorns in
# 把鱼放进去 放进去以后有两种炸法
There are two ways to fry the fish after putting it in
# 一种是蘸糊炸
One is dipping the batter and fry
# 一种是像这种混炸
One is like this, mixing then fry
# 就是把糊和鱼拌一块 这样的比较省
Just mix the batter and fish together. This way saves batter.
# 你要蘸糊炸呢 就是糊厚
If you dip the batter and fry, the coating is thick
# 咱们试一个
Let's try one
# 一般的来说 你看不能马上往下滴答
Generally speaking, the batter should not drip down right away
# 这糊就合适
This means the batter is suitable
# 这油温合适
The oil temperature is right
# 你看这糊 亮子
Look at this batter, Liangzi
# 倍儿匀 光溜
Very even, smooth
# 咱们这个糊就合适了
Our batter is suitable
# 这是两次炸熟 先定型
We will fry twice, first fix the shape
# 拉起来这鱼不能马上滴答汁儿
This fish shouldn't drip liquid right away
# 糊不能马上往下垂 那就糊稀了
The batter shouldn't drip immediately, otherwise the batter is too thin
# 油温大约在五六成热 定型
The oil temperature is about 50% to 60% (150-180 C) heat setting to fix the shape of the fish
# 你看二伯 小助手
Look at Er Bai, little assistant
# 二伯是我的小助手
Er Bai is my little assistant
# 看见了么 这老两位
Did you see these two?
# 大爷和二伯配合默契
Da Ye and Er Bai cooperate tacitly
# 也是会享受生活的好男人
They are good men who know how to enjoy life
# 这两口子做饭 这不也更快乐了
It’s happier for couple to cook together
# 先定型 炸到金黄色
Fix the shape first and deep-fried until golden brown
# 实际上早上喝粥炸点也好吃
In fact, it is good with porridge in the morning
# 把这渣子抄一下
Get rid of this fried crumbs
# 好了 走着 复炸一遍
Okay, let's go and fry it again
# 这也下锅是么 来啦
Isn't this going in as well? Here it goes
# 我没用那么多油
I didn't use too much oil
# 节省点油 我就把油温升的高一点
Save some oil, I will raise the oil temperature a bit higher
# 基本就好了 倍儿挺看着 饱满
Basically it's done. Looks pretty firm and full
# 咱就开始捞了
Let's start taking it out
# 外边买的外边都厚厚一层
The (fried fish) you bought outside has a very thick coating
# 里边的小鱼不大
But the fish inside is not big
# 看着炸出来个儿挺大的
Looks big
# 外边酥脆 里边鲜嫩
Crispy outside and tender inside
# 小黄鱼里边的肉一定得吃嫩嫩的那种
The flesh of yellow croaker need to be tender
# 您先尝第一口咸不咸
You take the first bite. Is it salty or not?
# 不咸的时候您蘸点椒盐 又是一个口
If it’s not salty, dip it in Sichuan pepper salt. Another flavor
# 我来
Let me try
# 咸淡味
Salty
# 这真够了
This is enough
# 这小骨头一提溜就全出去了
The bones are removed when you pick it up gently
# 我也来一个 随便挑一个
Let me have one, pick one
# 我挑一个儿大的
I want to pick a big one
# 没有太大的 我下手 就是武吃
No extremely big ones. I will use my hand, Wu Chi
# 咸淡味 咸淡味合适
Proper saltiness
# 但是这个椒盐里边加味精
But adding MSG in this Sichuan pepper salt
# 这确实是鲜度增加了 口感不一样
This indeed enhances umami flavor, and it tastes differently
# 它皮不是那么酥  但是它就是好吃
Its skin is not so crispy, but it is delicious
# 大爷这个就有这特点
The dish that Da Ye made has this feature:
# 你吃了一个 你就想第二个
You eat one, you want the second
# 这不吃白不吃了 不吃白不吃
Don’t waste the chance to eat.
# 我也来一个
I will also have one
# 现出锅好吃 香
It's delicious, when it just comes out of the pot